<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.anuragkr.in/</id><updated>2014-12-06T23:50:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Best Quora reads this week</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/12/best-quora-reads-this-week/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-06T23:50:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-12-06:posts/2014/12/best-quora-reads-this-week/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, so as the title suggests I have started this series of posts from quora. Now why would I do that? Well, staraight forward answer I wish to collect these awesome reads that comes across my Quora profile and I wanted a new topic to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXtZL/"&gt;What was it like to grow up in India in the 1990s&lt;/a&gt;
I am sure if you are a true Quora reader you would have seen this question many times. I bet you will smile reading the answer, only if you were born in the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXnpM"&gt;What are the biggest misconceptions that Indians have about India&lt;/a&gt; - Well, if you were born in an average middle class family, this answer needs no explanation. Speaking of which, I am glad I will never join that league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXnnW"&gt;What are some of the best travel and exploring places in India which are not overcrowded with tourists&lt;/a&gt; - This answer prompted me to start this series in the first place. The post is bit longer I agree but she had to cover all on her list. I have visited few of these and hoping I will visit them in near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXv1f"&gt;I am hearing the packages of 1 crores and 75 lakhs these days in IIT campus placements Where are they made to do their work in the US or India&lt;/a&gt; - I have no words for this, the answer explains it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXvue"&gt;If an IIT graduate does not get a job in the campus placements what are his options after graduation&lt;/a&gt; - Again a post worth mentioning, brave heart and bold decision. He is my also profile to be followed this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXvEI"&gt;What is it like being raised by relatively uneducated parents parents who have no graduate degree and arent in a business of any kind but earn a nominal salary&lt;/a&gt; - A inspiring post which makes me realize how sometimes we take things for granted and do not value them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw this iamge on Quora itself. Dont we just love Calvin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://qr.ae/qX9A4"&gt;&lt;img alt="alternate text" class="align-left" src="/images/calvin.jpeg" style="width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>Flask boilerplate for google app engine</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/11/flask-boilerplate-for-google-app-engine/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-11-30T04:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-11-30:posts/2014/11/flask-boilerplate-for-google-app-engine/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been over a year that I started writing codes and midst of that journey I felt the need to deploy some of my apps on a server. And there I started experimenting with different cloud hosting platform to deploy my apps. Starting with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.heroku.com/"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, I tried &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aws.amazon.com/"&gt;Amazon AWS&lt;/a&gt; and finally &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cloud.google.com/appengine/"&gt;Google App Engine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not go deep into explaining the differences between those three cloud providers. Just that for a beginner AWS proves to be a little too much to configure. It took me days to understand and eventually deploy the app. But then Heroku and GAE are much better options to test the waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like other Google services, GAE is also very easy to use, although there are certain limitations in terms of language and the database but then every cloud service has its baggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent consedrable amount of time with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, it was quite natural to go forward with it. But if you have ever used GAE you would know that Django is probably not a best choice for GAE. It has been &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1934925/1462730"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that the strengths of these two technologies do not align well. You tend to loose out on some of the wonderful features of Django on GAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little more digging around gave me a simpler &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/kamalgill/flask-appengine-template"&gt;Flask boilerplate&lt;/a&gt; for GAE. Ofcource it has been modified to leverage the model-view-controller logic from Django.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have hosted few static websites using the same and it was done in almost notime. I have still not used the models to interact with the database and will cover that in next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="google app engine"></category></entry><entry><title>Morning Blues</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/11/morning-blues/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-11-16T09:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-11-16:posts/2014/11/morning-blues/</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="morning blues" class="align-center" src="/images/morning.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened again, those few moments when you steal my soul away, just for a second or two.
I cannot see your beauty, for my eyes are closed. I have no clue of that, but I know you would blow my mind away when it happens for real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s your voice that shot me today. Observing every word you spelt, for you pronounce them so neatly. It still hums in my ears.
It was sweet but not like a lullaby, it never made me sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can compare it to a situation; a feather moving up your body, close enough that you can feel its movement and it gives you goose bumps. Or you can replace the feathers with a pair of lips. Mine.
Or when smoke enters into the lungs, you feel in, steadily it spreads nicotine in the body. Mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to hear a song, to preserve your memory for some time, but none were intoxicating enough to bring those words back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was always fond of your voice, way back when we were teens.
Everything attracted me towards you then, but it was difficult to stand out the strongest.
I can do now.
It’s one among many that attracts me; your absence no longer stands a barrier now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If ever you read this, just answer me a thing, how much of you is alcohol?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>PyconIndia 2014</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/09/pyconindia-2014/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-30T12:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-09-30:posts/2014/09/pyconindia-2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend marked the end of yet another awesome PyconIndia. This was not only the best PyconIndia experience for me but also for many others who have been a regular attendee since past years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As compared to last year, this time I choose to volunteer for the event which was an unique experience in its own. Although I missed the first keynote and few important sessions but I came to realized few key things, quoting from the presentation at PyconIndia, 'conference are more than just attending sessions'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="alternate text" class="align-center" src="/images/pycon_one.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I was just hopping from one Audi to another, which was definitely not so great experience. You always have videos on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; to watch those sessions but the physical interactions with people is one thing you wont get after the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between I was in the video team who shot the entire event, so cheers. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel discussion (Flask vs Django vs Web.py) on Day 2 was another delight, at then end of 45 minutes discussion, Django emerged as the clear winner. The votes were based out of an app made by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/twitortat"&gt;Aravind&lt;/a&gt; which calculated number of miscalls to numbers assigned to three frameworks. Here is a snapshot of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/twitortat/status/516263794352197632"&gt;votes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food, like every year was the center of attraction, heck it was even better than last years. Whenever I tend to invite people for Pycon, food remains my primary source to convince them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyconIndia in general gets good reception from developers across the country and being a volunteer you get to know them much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me sessions from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/kracetheking"&gt;Krace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/anandology"&gt;Anand&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/jackerhack"&gt;Kiran&lt;/a&gt; were feature of the PyconIndia 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://campushash.com/"&gt;CampusHash&lt;/a&gt; , finally launched their product at the event and I am waiting for the early invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with these &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/search?v=stream&amp;amp;q=%23pyconindia&amp;amp;src=tyah&amp;amp;mode=photos"&gt;images&lt;/a&gt; from the event.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Pyconindia2014"></category><category term="blog."></category></entry><entry><title>How to Install and configure Apache on Fedora 19</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/07/how-to-install-and-configure-apache-on-fedora-19/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-07-13:posts/2014/07/how-to-install-and-configure-apache-on-fedora-19/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Few days back I was juggling to install the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_HTTP_Server"&gt;apache&lt;/a&gt; web server on my local machine which has fedora 19. Information on the internet is scattered around and there isn't one tutorial which can you through the entire process. It tooks me quite some time to figure out the exact procedure and the below mentioned steps are the result of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume you have a previous knowledge of vim and its subsequesnt commands, if not this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.engadget.com/2012/07/10/vim-how-to/"&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; might help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="installing-apache-webserver"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing Apache webserver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
sudo yum install httpd
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="configure-apache-to-run-your-local-website"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Configure Apache to run your local website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
vim /etc/httpd/conf/httpd.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browse to the end of file (you do not need to change anything else) and append the following at bottom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;lt;VirtualHost *:80&amp;gt;
DocumentRoot /var/www/your-site-name
ServerName local.your-mysite-name
&amp;lt;/VirtualHost&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add your site (folder) name to DocumentRoot and ServerName. For example in my case it would be /var/www/site and local.site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: whatever site/folder-name you are adding above, must exists. If its not create such folder. After adding the above, you can save and close the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
vim /etc/hosts
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Append the following to the file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
127.0.0.1    local.your-site-name
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example in my case it will be: local.mysite. Now, save and close the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Start Apache:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
sudo service httpd start
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Check if apache is running or not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
sudo service httpd status
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
ps -eZ | grep httpd
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to view the httpd processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now access your site at the address you specified above, e.g. local.your-site-name .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note:  do not add www at the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="internet"></category></entry><entry><title>Keep Learning</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/07/keep-learning/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-05T01:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-07-05:posts/2014/07/keep-learning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Couples of minutes back I was watching &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=vXr-2hwTk58"&gt;Internet Own Boy&lt;/a&gt; and I don't have any opinions or views, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz"&gt;Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt; needs no introduction. My only advice will be go watch the documentary(if you haven't already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start of the post is little off the topic but the documentary made me realized one fact (there are many others) that I know so little of internet or information in general. At the age of 25 he was out there making a world better place for others. What am I doing at 23?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I had no answers to my own questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in 11th standard I dreamt of making this world better. Instead of just consuming what it has to offer giving things back to the society too, in whatever manner I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the lines, various personal issues took me away from it. I lost a very important person in my life and also lost a bit of myself. But I am here now (though not fully recovered ) at a stage where I can work on the same childhood dream. Now that I have a domain to concerntrate (that would be internet), I can narrow down my energies into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I capable enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I would say No, not enough but Hey no one here is born perfect of fully capable but I can always learn and teach myself. And and that what the post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Delight for online customers</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/06/delight-for-online-customers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-01T11:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-06-01:posts/2014/06/delight-for-online-customers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Online shopping was never in a better state than in 2014 and will probably improve in the coming years. With the recent deal of Flipkart and Myntra, the ecommerce scene in India has improved a great deal. Everything brings more rejoice for the online customers. Personally speaking my online purchases have significantly increased in the 3-4 years. And why not as an online customer I tend to get more benefits as compared to the offline markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live with few of my friends in Kolkata and we call ourselves as internet citizens. Majority of our time is spent in the internet world but at the same time we devote enough time for offline social interaction.
Coming back to topic, as internet citizens we make full use of our purchasing rights. You know the drill, getting coupons and discounts for every possible item.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="internet"></category></entry><entry><title>How to configure PhoneGap in Fedora 19</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/05/how-to-configure-phonegap-in-fedora-19/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-31T12:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-05-31:posts/2014/05/how-to-configure-phonegap-in-fedora-19/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Building android apps in native Java is cool but the only problem with this methodology is that you cannot port the same into other platforms (like Facebook, Windows etc). This drawback can be effectively removed if you use HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript to build the mobile apps. This is where &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://phonegap.com/"&gt;PhoneGap&lt;/a&gt; comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installation page of Phonegap gives some instruction on how to install some dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Npm and NodeJS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;To install Node you need to install some dependencies such as c++/gcc, which is used in compilation of the former:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ sudo yum install gcc-c++
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then install node. You can either do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ yum install nodejs
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;or you can install it from the source files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a: Download the source code from the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ cd Downloads
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ tarnode-v0.8.15.tar.gz (change the versions accordingly)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ cd node-v0.8.15
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ ./configure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo make install
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f: Add the path in system, if its not present:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ cd

$sudo vi .bash_profile
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;add these lines in the file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
PATH = $PATH:/usr/local/bin

export PATH
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Now that you have node, installation of npm will be very easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;get the source from Github&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;untar it, move into that directory and then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ ./configure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo make install
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ sudo npm install -g phonegap
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic" start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Phonegap should be installed now. Move into a directory where you wish to create a app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ phonegap create my-app

$ cd myapp

$ phonegap run android
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this moment if you have a mobile device connected to the system the app will be installed on the device itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="phonegap"></category><category term="Fedora"></category></entry><entry><title>entrepreneurship vs job</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/05/entrepreneurship-vs-job/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-23T12:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-05-23:posts/2014/05/entrepreneurship-vs-job/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today while I was loitering around, few conversations (from the past) made me smile. yes I also decided I would also write a piece on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;why our Indian culture promotes the culture of job searching instead of creating jobs for others, why not create a company instead of opting for MBAs and post grad degrees? My parents like any all caring parents in India wants me to take up a job after I complete my B.tech, which is quite natural considering the fact that they have invested in me for many years and now they wish I should live a happy and peaceful life. This is what any parent will wish for his/her child, right ? Perfectly normal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why not the other way around? Like how interesting it would have been if had they asked me to create a company instead of looking for jobs. (By the way I had already created one and its shut down as well. poor me!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, I examined the generations of my family history and no one had ever diverted from the searching-the-job attitude after college (I will be the first one perhaps). So, no one knows what its like there, this entrepreneurship is total mystery land for them. And people are afraid from stepping into unknown places. Perfectly normal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, then how we could change things around? The first step might be : jump into the pool of entrepreneurship and inspire the others to do the same (one may not succeed in the first attempt, someday down the line you might win and then there will be no appetite for your hunger). This is a very interesting &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ted.com/talks/cameron_herold_let_s_raise_kids_to_be_entrepreneurs.html"&gt;TED vedio&lt;/a&gt; which encourages people to create entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have made a start and I always energize my spirits by observing other young entrepreneurs making their mark in the world ex - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/varun067"&gt;Varun Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/deepakravindran"&gt;Deepak Ravindran&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And may be someday I will inspire others to take up entrepreneurship as a career option. But I have a long road ahead, one important message that I have learned from the past experiences :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="alternate text" class="align-center" src="/images/work.png" /&gt;
</summary><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing production apps on mobile</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/05/testing-production-apps-on-mobile/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-22T12:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-05-22:posts/2014/05/testing-production-apps-on-mobile/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have ADB and Eclipse IDE installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using Samsung Galaxy Pro to connect to fedora 19 but it shouldn't really matter if you have a different device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the eclipse toolkit, you have the option to run it directly on a device. It's rather quick to do so but the experience is same as that of emulator.  On your phone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Enable USB debugging (modern android versions this is present as Developers Option ) as well as installation of apk from sources other than the market (in the settings &amp;gt; security option).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;In the AndroidManifest.xml file , add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
android: debuggable=&amp;quot;True&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to the &amp;lt;application&amp;gt; element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Connect your device with your system via USB cable, then Open terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ adb devices
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you will get a unique id for the device attached. Keep a note of this id, we will be using this below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to add a udev rules file that contains a USB configuration for each type of device you want to use for development. In the rules file, each device manufacturer is identified by a unique vendor ID, as specified by the &lt;em&gt;ATTR{idVendor}&lt;/em&gt; property. For a list of vendor IDs, see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://developer.android.com/tools/device.html#VendorIds"&gt;vendor ids&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log in as root and create this file: /etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Use this format to add each vendor to the file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;usb&amp;quot;, ATTR{idVendor}==&amp;quot;0bb4&amp;quot;, MODE=&amp;quot;0666&amp;quot;, GROUP=&amp;quot;plugdev&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, the vendor ID is for HTC, change it according to your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now execute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
chmod a+r /etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your device is now configured, when testing apps from Eclipse IDE select this device when prompted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other ADB uses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After step 4 above, type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ adb shell
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this will list the root contents of your phone. Next if you do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ ls
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the files will be visible to you. Other operations such as: &lt;em&gt;cd, mkdir&lt;/em&gt; etc are also applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to know more about ADB operations type $ adb in your terminal, you will get all available commands to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://developer.android.com/tools/device.html"&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="phonegap"></category><category term="Fedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Starting with Pelican</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/05/starting-with-pelican/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-21T04:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-05-21:posts/2014/05/starting-with-pelican/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first rst post! After dealing with different blogging platforms I found Pelican perfect suited to needs. Its simple and easy to install, start, host and overall its written in Python. I have found a new open source library to contribute to. Further all my codes and articles will be hosted on github, so worries of creating a backup of my local system files.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="rst"></category><category term="pelican"></category></entry></feed>