<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/feeds/django.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.anuragkr.in/</id><updated>2015-01-17T11:30:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Starting out with Django (my experience)</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2015/01/starting-out-with-django-my-experience/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-17T11:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2015-01-17:posts/2015/01/starting-out-with-django-my-experience/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is not about how/why one should work on Django. Rather its a small recollection of my memories when I started with this popular Python framwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I was looking to start a new freelance project and thought Django will probably fit in the requirements very well. The very first thing I needed was the latest Django code and well, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.djangoproject.com/download/"&gt;djangoproject&lt;/a&gt; is the right place to look for the same.
A stream of old memories struck me at the very instant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting out with Django was not so good experince for me, I had really tough time learning the basics. It was not before 3 attempts (and 1 year) that I realized how things work in Django. I would spend long hours on the djangoproject site trying to gulp what the tutorial exactly meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, it was tough, considering the fact that I had little Python experince and I was in a hurry to create a web portal. Someone told (well, i read it on the internet) me Django is a good web framework. Looking back it now, I feel I should have started out with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flask.pocoo.org/"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; first. But instead i learned flask after experimenting with Django. As there was no one to guide me about the basics I made my own sets of mistakes. But hey! I learned a lot as well so I would reer them as my leaning curve :D .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="present"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Present&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django 1.7 is now the latest version and I am sure things must have improved a lot.
I know I am probably very late to even read the new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last experimented with Django 1.5, when I was building an initial prototype for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://geeklab.in"&gt;geeklab&lt;/a&gt; (the project never got completed) I was totally in favour of Django over Flask. But with latest developments in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://betaglide.com"&gt;Betaglide&lt;/a&gt; (yeah, thats where I work) and my learning with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cloud.google.com/appengine/"&gt;Google Appengine&lt;/a&gt;, I would say Flask is impressive as well.
I guess every framwork has its own merits and its upto us how/where we use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, enough of blabbering, I should get back to my project now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Python"></category><category term="frameworks"></category></entry></feed>