<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://anurag619.github.io/static_world/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://anurag619.github.io/static_world/feeds/just_for_fun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://anurag619.github.io/static_world/</id><updated>2014-05-23T12:01:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>entrepreneurship vs job</title><link href="http://anurag619.github.io/static_world/posts/2014/05/entrepreneurship-vs-job/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-23T12:01:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:anurag619.github.io/static_world,2014-05-23:posts/2014/05/entrepreneurship-vs-job/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today while I was loitering around, few conversations (from the past) made me smile. yes I also decided I would also write a piece on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;why our Indian culture promotes the culture of job searching instead of creating jobs for others, why not create a company instead of opting for MBAs and post grad degrees? My parents like any all caring parents in India wants me to take up a job after I complete my B.tech, which is quite natural considering the fact that they have invested in me for many years and now they wish I should live a happy and peaceful life. This is what any parent will wish for his/her child, right ? Perfectly normal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why not the other way around? Like how interesting it would have been if had they asked me to create a company instead of looking for jobs. (By the way I had already created one and its shut down as well. poor me!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, I examined the generations of my family history and no one had ever diverted from the searching-the-job attitude after college (I will be the first one perhaps). So, no one knows what its like there, this entrepreneurship is total mystery land for them. And people are afraid from stepping into unknown places. Perfectly normal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, then how we could change things around? The first step might be : jump into the pool of entrepreneurship and inspire the others to do the same (one may not succeed in the first attempt, someday down the line you might win and then there will be no appetite for your hunger). This is a very interesting &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ted.com/talks/cameron_herold_let_s_raise_kids_to_be_entrepreneurs.html"&gt;TED vedio&lt;/a&gt; which encourages people to create entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have made a start and I always energize my spirits by observing other young entrepreneurs making their mark in the world ex - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/varun067"&gt;Varun Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/deepakravindran"&gt;Deepak Ravindran&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And may be someday I will inspire others to take up entrepreneurship as a career option. But I have a long road ahead, one important message that I have learned from the past experiences :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="alternate text" class="align-center" src="/images/work.png" /&gt;
</summary><category term="life"></category></entry></feed>