<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.anuragkr.in/</id><updated>2015-05-05T01:20:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>So whats happening around?</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2015/05/so-whats-happening-around/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-05T01:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2015-05-05:posts/2015/05/so-whats-happening-around/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I will forever wonder “where did my craze for writing go?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write one article every 2-3 months now when I used to finish the same in an hour. Where is the passion now? I wonder if there was any passion in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happens to be my post from the new Macbook, so cheers to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to make this post unstructured. Broken lines/sentences, meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not contributed to any open source projects for a long time now and I dont intend to either. I dont feel the need to do so. I have adopted more outdoor activities but still end up sitting infront of laptop for considerably long enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found new writer and his site &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://austinkleon.com/"&gt;Austin Kleon&lt;/a&gt; strange name I don’t know how to pronounce that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I found him? Well, surfing. Thats how I discover new things and that is how I learned about blogging in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not worked on any personal projects either and nothing is in the pipline either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am getting a strong urge of taking a coffee right at this moment. So, I will leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be the point of living, do what you wish not because others are doing. That might answer the title of this unstructured post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Morning Blues</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/11/morning-blues/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-11-16T01:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-11-16:posts/2014/11/morning-blues/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It happened again, those few moments when you steal my soul away, just for a second or two. I cannot see your beauty, for my eyes are closed. I have no clue of that, but I know you would blow my mind away when it happens for real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s your voice that shot me today. Observing every word you spelt, for you pronounce them so neatly. It still hums in my ears. It was sweet but not like a lullaby, it never made me sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can compare it to a situation; a feather moving up your body, close enough that you can feel its movement and it gives you goose bumps. Or you can replace the feathers with a pair of lips. Mine. Or when smoke enters into the lungs, you feel in, steadily it spreads nicotine in the body. Mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to hear a song, to preserve your memory for some time, but none were intoxicating enough to bring those words back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was always fond of your voice, way back when we were teens. Everything attracted me towards you then, but it was difficult to stand out the strongest. I can do now. It’s one among many that attracts me; your absence no longer stands a barrier now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If ever you read this, just answer me a thing, how much of you is alcohol?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Keep Learning</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/07/keep-learning/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-05T01:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-07-05:posts/2014/07/keep-learning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Couples of minutes back I was watching &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=vXr-2hwTk58"&gt;Internet Own Boy&lt;/a&gt; and I don't have any opinions or views, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz"&gt;Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt; needs no introduction. My only advice will be go watch the documentary(if you haven't already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start of the post is little off the topic but the documentary made me realized one fact (there are many others) that I know so little of internet or information in general. At the age of 25 he was out there making a world better place for others. What am I doing at 23?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I had no answers to my own questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in 11th standard I dreamt of making this world better. Instead of just consuming what it has to offer giving things back to the society too, in whatever manner I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the lines, various personal issues took me away from it. I lost a very important person in my life and also lost a bit of myself. But I am here now (though not fully recovered ) at a stage where I can work on the same childhood dream. Now that I have a domain to concerntrate (that would be internet), I can narrow down my energies into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I capable enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I would say No, not enough but Hey no one here is born perfect of fully capable but I can always learn and teach myself. And and that what the post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>