<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.anuragkr.in/</id><updated>2014-07-05T01:20:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Keep Learning</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/07/keep-learning/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-05T01:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-07-05:posts/2014/07/keep-learning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Couples of minutes back I was watching &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=vXr-2hwTk58"&gt;Internet Own Boy&lt;/a&gt; and I don't have any opinions or views, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz"&gt;Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt; needs no introduction. My only advice will be go watch the documentary(if you haven't already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start of the post is little off the topic but the documentary made me relaized one (there are many others) that I know so little of internet or information in general. At the age of 25 he was out there making a world better for others. What am I doing at 23?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I had no answers to my own questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in 11th standard I dreamt of making this world better. Instead of just consuming what it has to offer but also giving things back to the society, in whatever manner I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the lines various personal issues took me away from it. I lost a very important person in my life and I also lost a bit of myself. But now I am here now (though not fully recovered ) at a stage where I can work on the same childhood dream. Now that I have a domain to concerntrate (that would be internet), I can narrow down my energies into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I capable enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I would say No, not enough but Hey no one here is born perfect of fully capable but I can always learn and teach myself. And and that what the post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>