<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/feeds/pycon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.anuragkr.in/</id><updated>2014-09-30T12:30:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>PyconIndia 2014</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/09/pyconindia-2014/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-30T12:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-09-30:posts/2014/09/pyconindia-2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend marked the end of yet another awesome PyconIndia. This was not only the best PyconIndia experience for me but also for many others who have been a regular attendee since past years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As compared to last year, this time I choose to volunteer for the event which was an unique experience in its own. Although I missed the first keynote and few important sessions but I came to realized few key things, quoting from the presentation at PyconIndia, 'conference are more than just attending sessions'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="alternate text" class="align-center" src="/images/pycon_one.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I was just hopping from one Audi to another, which was definitely not so great experience. You always have videos on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/inpycon"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; to watch those sessions but the physical interactions with people is one thing you wont get after the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between I was in the video team who shot the entire event, so cheers. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel discussion (Flask vs Django vs Web.py) on Day 2 was another delight, at then end of 45 minutes discussion by the elites, Django emerged as the clear winner. The votes were based out of an made by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/twitortat"&gt;Aravind&lt;/a&gt; which calculated number of miscalls to numbers assigned to three frameworks. Here is a snapshot of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/twitortat/status/516263794352197632"&gt;votes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food, like every year was the center of attraction, heck it was even better than last years. Whenever I tend to invite people for Pycon, food remains my primary source to convince them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyconIndia in general gets good reception from developers across the country and being a volunteer you get to know them much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me sessions from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/kracetheking"&gt;Krace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/anandology"&gt;Anand&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/jackerhack"&gt;Kiran&lt;/a&gt; were feature of the PyconIndia 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://campushash.com/"&gt;CampusHash&lt;/a&gt; , finally launched their product at the event and I am waiting for the early invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with these &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/search?v=stream&amp;amp;q=%23pyconindia&amp;amp;src=tyah&amp;amp;mode=photos"&gt;images&lt;/a&gt; from the event.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Pyconindia2014"></category><category term="blog."></category></entry></feed>