<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Static_World</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/feeds/quora.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.anuragkr.in/</id><updated>2014-12-06T23:50:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Best Quora reads this week</title><link href="http://blog.anuragkr.in/posts/2014/12/best-quora-reads-this-week/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-06T23:50:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Anurag</name></author><id>tag:blog.anuragkr.in,2014-12-06:posts/2014/12/best-quora-reads-this-week/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, so as the title suggests I have started this series of posts from quora. Now why would I do that? Well, staraight forward answer I wish to collect these awesome reads that comes across my Quora profile and I wanted a new topic to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXtZL/"&gt;What was it like to grow up in India in the 1990s&lt;/a&gt;
I am sure if you are a true Quora reader you would have seen this question many times. I bet you will smile reading the answer, only if you were born in the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXnpM"&gt;What are the biggest misconceptions that Indians have about India&lt;/a&gt; - Well, if you were born in an average middle class family, this answer needs no explanation. Speaking of which, I am glad I will never join that league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXnnW"&gt;What are some of the best travel and exploring places in India which are not overcrowded with tourists&lt;/a&gt; - This answer prompted me to start this series in the first place. The post is bit longer I agree but she had to cover all on her list. I have visited few of these and hoping I will visit them in near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXv1f"&gt;I am hearing the packages of 1 crores and 75 lakhs these days in IIT campus placements Where are they made to do their work in the US or India&lt;/a&gt; - I have no words for this, the answer explains it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXvue"&gt;If an IIT graduate does not get a job in the campus placements what are his options after graduation&lt;/a&gt; - Again a post worth mentioning, brave heart and bold decision. He is my also profile to be followed this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://qr.ae/qXvEI"&gt;What is it like being raised by relatively uneducated parents parents who have no graduate degree and arent in a business of any kind but earn a nominal salary&lt;/a&gt; - A inspiring post which makes me realize how sometimes we take things for granted and do not value them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saw this iamge on Quora itself. Dont we just love Calvin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://qr.ae/qX9A4"&gt;&lt;img alt="alternate text" class="align-left" src="/images/calvin.jpeg" style="width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><category term="life"></category></entry></feed>